Akash Panchal

Software Development Engineer

Software engineer with 6+ years of experience in designing, implementing and debugging backend software components, cloud services and Mobile SDKs in an Agile environment. Developed products primarily using Python, Java and AWS services. Excited to learn new languages, frameworks and platforms.



Work History

2021-10

Software Development Engineer 2 - Amazon Appstore

- present

Amazon

- Design and implemented window manipulation for Automatic testing of Android Apps on Windows, around 200K apps will be tested using the same.
- Improved UX for promotion portal on App store retail page and Developer portal
- Optimised the queries and data retrieval time for App details by 50%
- Mentored an intern and contributed in project planning in Agile

2018-12

Backend Software Engineer - Secure Home Platform

- 2021-07 *McAfee*

Working as a Backend Software Engineer to provide custom SHP solution to an ISP partner.

- Decreased the DB storage and Network calls up to 40% for a Router API by optimizing data flow design.
- Fixed the critical subscription failure cases that led to DDOS-like attacks from routers.

2017-11

Android Software Engineer - Safe Connect

- 2018-12

Android SDK and App developer for the VPN client App - Safe Connect

- Implemented a VPN SDK wrapper for the partner Apps and core App to consume
- Developed custom Network state-machine to support Auto-start VPN and Activity-log features

2016-06

Backend Software Engineer - Mobile Apps Scanner

- 2017-10

- Achieved higher throughput of the app scanners by slashing repeat scanning of the Android Apps up to 5000 per day.
- Designed and Implemented a pipe-filter service to process APK data using pluggable codes.

98

Side Projects

- 2021-07 Webpage Summarization

McAfee

https://github.com/akashp1712/summarize-webpage

- 2021-07 Python cheat sheets

https://github.com/akashp1712/awesome-python-cheatsheets

Personal Info

Website

https://akashpanchal.com

Emai

akashp1712@gmail.com

Phone

+91 8722513026

LinkedIn

https://linkedin.com/in/akashpanchal

GitHub

https://github.com/akashp1712

Address

A4, 4th cross, Bellandur main road, Bellandur, Bengaluru - 560103

Medium

https://akashp1712.medium.com



Python

Java AWS

Data Structures & Algorithms

ReactJS



Education

2014-07 - 2016-05

Computer Science, M.Tech

Nirma University, Ahmedabad